...向你致敬。
温柔一点，汉诺。
我们呼唤你
以你们伟大的名字
来帮助我们。
击败罗马人。
摧毁他们的船只，
他们的战争引擎，
和他们的士兵。
我们会取得胜利。
奥扎尔斯切斯。
阿利沙特。
汉诺。
你没有做
今天的奉献。
我更喜欢牺牲一个罗马人。
你在哪里，
I am, too.
And where you are,
I am, too, forever.
My wife.
The wind is too strong.
Furl sail and strike water.
Furl sail,
strike water!
Furl sail
and strike water!
Strike water!
They have no lands
but the ones they've stolen.
Wherever they go,
they leave destruction
and call it peace.
This is the last free city
in Africa Nova.
Today, we go into battle.
Pray that your god is with you.
If he is not, he is no god.
We've nothing to fear.
Where death is, we are not.
Where we are,
death is not.
Stay together and listen
for my commands.
Your eyes up
and your head out.
Fire!
Ready your weapons!
Again!
We're ablaze on the right!
Keep formation!
Pull!
Archers ready.
Release!
Nock!
画！
松动的！
弓箭手！
火！
- 升起塔！
- 向后退！
继续转动。
吊桥掉下来！
吊桥卡住了！
先生！
松动的！
后退。
弓箭手！
那里！
杀了她！
阿利沙特！
阿利沙特。
I'll wait for you.
Check all the bodies!
Leave nothing!
I claim this city...
for the glory of Rome.
Vae victis.
Woe to the conquered.
Next!
Move it!
-Down the stairs!
-Downstairs!
Hey.
What damage have they
done you, eh?
Lift it up. Easy, easy.
Hold that.
Arishat?
I am sorry, my son.
I have not long.
This galley
is sailing us to something
I cannot endure.
I am ready... to be taken
to another place.
Stay here a while longer.
I remember well when you
first were brought to us.
A lonely boy from the desert.
Guileless.
Afraid.
You embraced everything
we taught you.
You found Arishat's love.
Your soul was replenished.
When I die,
my ancestors will meet me
in the next world.
Who will meet you?
Hanno,
I am done.
Do not let them change
what you are.
Have you seen this boy?
Eama! Eama!
You must
go alone now, Hanno.
Never let them find you.
Go. Go.
Acacius! Acacius! Acacius!
Emperor Geta.
Emperor Caracalla.
General Acacius.
I have taken Numidia
in your names
that your dominion
may eclipse that
of every emperor
that came before you.
Crown him with laurels,
brother.
Acacius! Acacius! Acacius!
In honor
of your conquest,
there will be games
in the Colosseum.
I require no games
in my honor.
Serving the Senate
and the people of Rome
is honor enough for me.
You are too modest,
Acacius.
It does not suit a general
as accomplished as yourself.
The glory is yours,
not mine.
I only ask for
从战争中得到一些喘息的机会
花时间
和我的妻子。
你的妻子，是的。
记住特权
我们已经准许她了吗？
她现在在哪里
忽视这样的场合？
有胜利
但尚未到来。
波斯。
印度。
两者……都必须被征服。
罗马有很多主题。
她必须喂饱他们。
他们可以吃战争。
你的胜利
将被庆祝
作为致敬
走向伟大
of the Roman people.
Go to hell!
Macrinus of Thysdrus,
master of gladiators!
Stay close.
Aediles
and the town councilors,
distinguished guests,
citizens of Antium,
behold the fate
of the conquered enemies
of Rome:
The barbarian Numidians
and their chieftain,
Jugurtha!
This one is interesting.
I'll buy him.
Halt! Who goes there?
General.
My lady.
I thank the gods
that brought you back home safe.
Thank the Army.
They protected me.
Mm.
Let me feed you.
Go.
To the wall.
The arena
is a sacred temple.
For the bravest of you,
the road to glory
runs through the arena.
The arena turns slaves
into gladiators
and gladiators into free men.
You have worms.
I know this one.
He eats monkeys.
Go. Sit. Eat.
You.
Hanno, get up.
What is your native language?
I speak them all.
You don't answer because
you can't or because you won't?
Mm, all right.
Violence...
is the universal language.
Viggo,
put him through his paces.
He can fight an ape.
Let's see if he can fight a man.
Enough!
Very good.
Hose him down.
Bring him to me.
Ah!
A strong jaw.
Good arms.
Better smell.
You will do well.
It is an art,
choosing gladiators.
Some choose entertainers.
Some choose brute force.
I choose rage.
Crowd loves blood.
And they love those who
love blood as much as they do.
而你，我的朋友，愤怒
从你身上倾泻而出，就像……
像牛奶一样...
来自妓女的乳头。
你会
相当战斗机。
不适合你。
你说得对，
你不为我而战。
我把你放进戒指里
你要么战斗，要么死亡。
选择权在你。
但谁的头
我可以给你吗
这能满足这种愤怒吗？
整个罗马军队的。
太多了。
毫米。
The general will do.
General?
-General Acacius?
-Mm.
Use your rage
in my service,
and you will have his head
ready for your sword.
Serve me and I will serve you.
Deny me...
and you will die.
There are times I wished
you'd abandoned me
rather than
fight their wars.
I've made my choice.
I can live with it.
But my patience with those two
is at an end.
Leta?
You may go to your quarters now.
We need nothing more.
To hear wives and mothers
mourning their dead
on that beach at Numidia...
Lucilla.
No more.
I will not waste
another generation
of young men for their vanity.
If I fight another campaign,
it must be to depose them.
When will your troops
arrive?
They land at Ostia
in ten days.
How many of them will be
loyal to you alone?
All of them.
The emperors do not have
the support of the people.
The people are weary
of the madness, the tyranny.
What is the dream of Rome
if her people are not free?
Enjoy yourself,
everyone,
to excess!
Thank you. Thank you.
Oh!
Please, drink.
Ah! Excuse me. Macrinus!
I knew the provinces
were not enough for you.
-I'm just here for the games.
-Ah, well,
you won't be disappointed.
罗马拥有所有比赛
像你这样的男人喜欢玩。
像我这样的男人，Thraex？
像我们这样的男人。
我知道罗马什么也没发生
除非你先尝过。
第241章
我来这里的目的是什么？
第242章
你很快就会知道。
我们听到的是什么
关于你感兴趣
参加竞选
去参议院，马克里努斯？
我？不，我是，呃…
我什至不知道如何
使用算盘。
第247章
但我确实明白
这是习惯
为您的客人
to make wagers
at these affairs?
How large a sum
did you have in mind?
A thousand gold denarii?
Two.
Two?
Denarii.
Stand back! Stand back!
My emperors.
Lords, ladies and gentlemen,
and senators.
For your entertainment,
the art of combat!
May I present
the barbarian versus,
from my own stable,
the mighty Vichek!
-This is your gladiator?
-It is.
Three rounds,
hand to hand.
Swords!
We want swords.
A fight to the death.
No quarter to be offered...
or given.
Fight now!
Brother,
let's not kill each other
for their amusement.
Remarkable!
Thraex, he looked expensive.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
Remarkable.
From where do you hail?
Speak.
我说说话。
第279章
他来自殖民地，
陛下。
他的母语
他只明白这一点。
第281章
“地狱之门
昼夜开放。
第282章
下降过程平稳，
方法很简单。
第283章
但...
第284章
从地狱回来
第285章
并观看欢快的天空，
第286章
在这个任务中
和强大的劳动谎言。”
第287章
维吉尔，陛下。
诗！
第289章
-非常聪明，马克林努斯。
-谢谢。
我已经变得如此无聊
但你让我很惊讶。
第291章
To amuse you is my only wish.
We are amused,
we are amused.
We are amused.
And we all look forward
to seeing your poet
perform in the arena.
As do I, Your Majesties.
Thank you.
Viggo?
Come with me.
You fought well today,
but you were lucky, too.
The lines you recited.
You didn't learn that
in Africa, I know that.
-A good verse travels far.
-Mm.
Who taught you poetry?
A captured Roman officer.
I was posted guard over him
and he used to tell us tales
to pass the time.
And what became
of this prisoner?
Oh, we ate him.
As barbarians do.
And where were you born?
Why does my past matter
if it is my future
to die for you in the arena?
Tell me what use have I
for Roman money.
A gladiator
can buy his own freedom.
His liberty.
The Roman dream.
No, the slave dreams
not of freedom
but of a slave
to call his own.
Cicero.
Is that what you were
raised on, Macrinus?
What did you have to do
for Roman money?
You promised me a head.
Earn your keep and you
can have anyone's head.
Father,
protect us and guide us.
Senators.
My lady.
我的女士，我希望我们是
在更好的时代相遇。
第332章
更好的时代将会到来。
第333章
我们为什么在这里？
第334章
为了夺回这座城市。
第335章
并恢复罗马
到她应该去的地方。
第336章
一次令人兴奋的冒险。
第337章
-什么时候？
- 比赛最后一天。
第338章
我的军队等待我的命令
在奥斯蒂亚。
第339章
五千士兵
忠于我...
将进入罗马
然后是罗马斗兽场，
第341章
他们将在哪里
逮捕皇帝
第342章
为了他们的罪行
反对参议院
第343章
and their people.
Uh, this plan
is ambitious and risky.
Rome will be yours
to administer and to--
Marcus Aurelius talked of
restoring power to the Senate,
but that was a generation ago.
Much has changed.
The people
have not seen hope
for many years.
But with time...
and guidance...
Lucilla, you are the daughter
of Marcus Aurelius.
He had my loyalty.
And so do you.
Senator Thraex?
Politics follows power,
my lady.
Take back
what is rightfully yours...
and the Senate
will support you.
Thank you.
Food! Food!
When I was told of this place,
they never mentioned
the stink.
That would be Hanno.
Well, you'll have to
put up with me as I am.
And what's that up there?
A wolf?
The twins there,
they were outcasts.
Left in the hills to die.
That wolf found them and she
suckled them on her milk.
由动物抚养长大。
这是他们的血液。
第369章
你怎么知道这个地方的？
我知道混乱
他们带来了。
第371章
这座城市感染着
它所触及的一切。
第372章
我从来没有梦想过
它会这么大。
第373章
不要上当。
第374章
这座城市已经病了。
第375章
食物！食物！
第376章
你！野蛮人渣！
第377章
帮我。
请帮我！
第378章
-啊！
-Thraex。
第379章
关于我们的赌注。
啊。野蛮人。
第381章
Yes, I haven't forgotten,
I always repay my debts.
I was merely
going to suggest
that perhaps your luck
might change.
Shall we say
double or quits?
-Ah.
Get back!
Fresh meat.
Line up! Line up!
Play! Play!
Emperor Caracalla.
Emperor Geta.
Citizens of Rome!
These sacred games
are held to honor
the victory of Rome
over the barbarians of Numidia.
Go! Go!
And to honor
Rome's legionary commander,
General Justus Acacius!
Long live Acacius!
And with him
Lucilla, the daughter
of Emperor Marcus Aurelius.
-Lucilla!
-Mother of Rome!
Acacius.
General.
Acacius! Acacius! Acacius!
Speak to them.
Speak to us!
I am not an orator
or a politician.
I am a soldier.
I have seen bravery
in men and women during war.
And even once in this arena.
So if you ask anything
of the gods...
ask for that same bravery.
Because Rome needs it now.
Acacius! Acacius! Acacius!
From the South Gate,
fighters from the stable
of Macrinus of Thysdrus!
From the stables
of Emperors Caracalla
and Geta themselves,
不败冠军：
第424章
破坏者格莱西奥！
第425章
抓住。
第426章
第427章
凯撒万岁！
第428章
糖！糖！糖！
第429章
抱在一起，当它
收费，撞墙。
第430章
我为什么要这么做？
第431章
抓住！
第432章
第433章
休息！
第434章
胆小鬼！
第435章
到墙边去！
第436章
快点！
第437章
兄弟，就是那个诗人，
不是吗？
第438章
我不记得了。
第439章
那个夜晚很模糊。
第440章
“地狱之门
昼夜开放。
第441章
平滑描述——”
我忘记了。
第442章
“平稳下降……”
第443章
“下降是平稳的，
第444章
方法很简单。”
第445章
盾！
第446章
怜悯！怜悯！怜悯！
第447章
血。
第448章
露西拉，
第449章
我们要怜悯吗？
怜悯。
第451章
没有怜悯！
第452章
你的生活已经
众神幸免——
第453章
I would sooner face your blade
than accept Roman mercy!
Kill! Kill! Kill!
Hanno! Hanno! Hanno!
The road to freedom doesn't
run through the arena.
It leads to this.
Go to your cells.
Hanno! Hanno! Hanno!
Come on, let's go.
"Gates of hell
are open night and day.
Smooth is the descent...
...easy is the way."
There, there, there, there.
And I've got you.
I'm Maximus,
the savior of Rome!
Scatto and Argento.
Lucius is safe?
Lucius!
Lucius,
you're the sole heir
to the throne now.
There are men
who want to kill you
so they can take power.
I promise I'll bring you back
as soon as it's safe.
Mother, why can't you
come with me?
I... I have to
stay here for your sake.
And for the sake of Rome.
记住你是谁。
第480章
我爱你。
第481章
第482章
来。
第483章
把你的腿给我。
第484章
去。去！
第485章
所以...
第486章
你叫什么名字？
第487章
我是拉维。我是一名医生。
第488章
因为……更多的人死去
受感染的伤口
第489章
比在外面、在竞技场上。
第490章
这个需要清洗一下
它需要缝合并且
第491章
它会很痛。
第492章
毫米。
第493章
这是恶魔之息
和鸦片。
第494章
是为了止痛吧
第495章
你应该吸气。
第496章
我来过这里
这么久了，
第497章
我什至不再注意到了。
第498章
我做过更多次截肢手术
我数不过来。
第499章
-你在哪里学的手艺？
-你为什么这么问？
你的手很重。
我曾经是
我自己也是一名角斗士。
啊。
你会打败我吗？
当然，在你的巅峰时期。
以你现在的状态，
I could best you now.
Luckily for you,
I have put down my sword.
So now I spend my days
saving lives
instead of taking them.
And why such a change
so late in life?
What we do in life
echoes in eternity.
I feel like
I know those words.
I can't take credit.
It's written on
one of the tombs.
Over the bones of a gladiator.
My champion!
I smell Devil's Breath!
My... champion.
Did you hear that crowd?
-Did you hear that crowd?
-Mm-hm.
You have something.
I knew it from the start.
-Did you now?
-Yes. The Greeks call it...
thymos.
Smoke.
Rage.
That rage is your gift.
Like the great Achilles.
Never let it go.
It will carry you
to greatness,
my champion.
Thank you
for inviting me.
这确实是一种荣幸。
第534章
我听说你是
法庭的谈话。
第535章
是的。
第536章
我们以前见过面。
第537章
-我们有吗？
-很久以前。
第538章
在哪里？
第539章
我当时在服役
你父亲的军队
关于他的非洲竞选活动。
第541章
你服务过
和我父亲？
第542章
毫米。
第543章
我有幸
第544章
阅读的
他的《沉思》。
第545章
毫米。
第546章
“最好的报复
第547章
is to be unlike him
who performed the injury."
I hear you've been
arming half the legions
in the entire empire,
and here, now, in Rome...
you're gaining influence
by sponsoring gladiators.
I do it for the love
of the sport.
And where did you find
these gladiators?
They're usually
prisoners of war.
Or vagrants.
Why do you ask?
A man can choose to fight...
and stay alive.
It's the same in life as it is
in the arena, is it not?
Who is this?
That is my father
as a youth.
She had a child?
Mm.
It's common knowledge.
When Commodus was killed,
-the boy disappeared.
-Mm.
-But who would care?
-Lucilla would care.
-More wine!
He was of the royal bloodline,
after all.
And his father?
Ostensibly,
Lucius Verus.
See, it was
an arranged marriage.
She was 14.
-Mm.
-Females were not his taste.
-Nor mine, some days.
-Nor yours!
No, no, no.
By rumor, you see, she took lovers.
And by rumor, the real father...
was Commodus.
-Brotherly love, you see?
-Yeah.
If he died,
-there has to be remains.
-Mm.
And if he lived,
that would make him about...
Um, well,
let's work it out.
-He was about 12 when he died?
-Yes.
So that would make him...
My lady.
Gracchus.
-Please come.
-Thank you.
Gladiator...
do you know me?
Do you have a family?
A wife. Arishat.
Arishat.
She was killed
under your husband's command.
Rome drowns
in its own blood.
And yet you enjoy
the pleasures of the Colosseum.
There is much
you do not understand.
Lucius.
I do not know
who you think I am.
My name is Hanno,
and I have no mother,
or none that I can remember.
I'm so sorry.
If your son were here,
I feel sure he would tell you
not to grieve him.
For he would not be the boy
that you sent away.
That boy is dead.
You may think
I have little worth.
I betrayed you.
But I need you to know...
if you will not have
your mother's love,
then take
your father's strength.
You need it.
His name was
Maximus Decimus Meridius.
And I see him in you.
Get out.
My lady, we must go at once!
Lucius, you were loved
by myself
and by your father.
Your name
was on his lips--
Get out!
Lucius is alive.
Are you certain?
Yes.
I know my son.
I spoke to him
tonight.
He may be lost to me
for what I did,
but he lives.
The third day of the games
is tomorrow.
Most fighters won't survive.
Acacius,
you must help him.
-Help him?
-Yes.
I failed him then.
I know I did.
I cannot fail him now.
The army is in Ostia.
If we wait a few days...
He could be dead
by then.
Acacius,
I would willingly
give my life for Rome,
but I will not
give my son's.
And one.
And two.
还有一个。
第641章
一起。
时机，时机，时机！
第642章
还有一个。还有两个。
第643章
还有一个。
第644章
暂停，暂停！
第645章
我们不会走远
像这样。
第646章
只有他。你去。
第647章
去！
第648章
让我们看看你能走多远
没有你的团队，就靠你自己。
第649章
准备好？
一！
第651章
还有两个！
第652章
时机，时机！
第653章
来吧，更多！
第654章
更多的！
第655章
离开他。
第656章
这只是
醋，我的朋友。
第657章
将有
不再给你鸦片了。
第658章
还有很多痛苦在等待
为了下辈子的你。
第659章
我不知道你为什么这样
贪婪于此。
你是自由人吗，拉维？
第661章
“自由的。”
第662章
我是。毫米。
第663章
我放下了剑
第664章
我发誓永远不会
再次拿起它。
第665章
然而
你选择这个地狱吗？
第666章
嗯嗯。
第667章
你以前的家是什么？
第668章
瓦拉纳西。
第669章
那你为什么不回去呢？
我希望我能。
第671章
但...
第672章
-我遇到了一个女人。
-啊。
第673章
-永远都是女人。
-总是。
第674章
她来自伦敦。
不列颠尼亚。你知道。
第675章
所以现在...
第676章
我们的儿子们，
他们只说拉丁语。
第677章
女儿的眼睛，
它们和你的一样蓝色。
第678章
我们现在是罗马人了。
第679章
我是听故事长大的
在我祖父的膝盖上。
他曾经说话
罗马的梦想。
第681章
原来是那么脆弱，
你只能低声说……
第682章
否则它就会消失。
第683章
所以，
第684章
这个梦是什么？
第685章
所有人都可以居住的罗马
并受到公平法律的保护。
第686章
元老院的罗马。
第687章
充满希望的罗马。
第688章
你的祖父，
他听起来像个危险的人。
第689章
嗯。
情况对你不利。
第691章
赔率
总是反对我。
第692章
别担心，老头子。
第693章
呃？
第694章
-你应该休息一下。嗯？
-毫米。
你的男人会需要你
领导他们明天。
这是关于生存的。
第697章
存活！
以波塞冬之名，
我们庆祝荣耀
海战的。
他们有弓箭手。
做好准备。
听我的命令。
第702章
呆在一起
并拉为一体，是吗？
是的！
-是的？
-是的！
今天我们重温一下
萨拉米斯海战！
特洛伊木马
对抗波斯人！
-划桨！
-桨！
And... pull!
Archers!
Pull!
Pull! To my time!
And... now!
Left side! Ready, and
ship oars now!
Oars in! Oars in!
Get down!
And pull! And pull!
Don't stop!
Pull!
And right!
Ready to ram!
And brace! Brace!
Everyone regroup!
Praetorians!
Hanno! Hanno! Hanno!
Move, move.
In the name of the emperors...
the victor is Hanno!
Who did this?
Who did this?!
-It was me!
-I did it!
-I did it! I did it! I did it!
-It was me!
Geta will want retribution
for all of you.
Did you learn to shoot
in the same place
you learned to recite poetry?
Be glad it wasn't me,
or that arrow
would have found you.
Be seated.
I have news for you.
He's here, sir.
Oh, still here.
Macrinus.
Welcome.
Yes, I'm listening.
You know
this is my house now.
Your debt to me is
over 10,000 denarii.
You know that.
I have other things. Uh...
Cattle. Art!
Truth, then.
What do you... want?
Truth.
That's what I want.
Nothing happens in Rome
without your knowledge.
You have
the senators' trust.
Lucilla's trust.
More importantly,
you have my trust.
You wish my... loyalty?
I own...
your house.
I want your loyalty.
I...
-Tell me.
-I have heard...
of a plot...
-to dethrone the emperors.
-Yes.
But the plan
has been delayed, uh...
A gladiator is to be rescued
from the arena.
-Tonight.
-Mm.
-I don't know why.
-I know why. I know who.
Pack.
Quickly.
Open up!
Open for
the emperors' guard!
My Lady, come with us.
Thanks to the civic virtue
of men like Thraex
and Macrinus,
your insurrection
has been revealed.
The honor,
罗马的尊严
已赐予你...
第784章
这一切都被你放弃了
因你的背叛。
第785章
拜托了，木塔天皇。
第786章
如果你愿意的话就折磨我吧
第787章
但别教训我。
第788章
你的名字
将会被遗忘！
第789章
迷失在历史之中。
第790章
你该死，
一般的。
第791章
-你笑了。
-你该死的我？
第792章
我不在乎。
第793章
一切都会随着时间被遗忘。
帝国衰落。皇帝也是如此。
第794章
为什么要等？
第795章
-我现在就把他开膛破肚！
-不，不，不！
第796章
随他们去吧。来！来！
第797章
他的死必须公开。
民众？
把他的内脏挂起来
从城门出来！
并将她钉死在十字架上！
把她钉在十字架上！
把他们带走！
嘘！嘘！嘘！
谢谢你，马克里努斯。
快点。
在这最后的日子里，
我开始想你了
不作为主题
但作为一个真正的朋友。
谢谢。
太感谢了。
但作为朋友，
我必须建议谨慎行事。
阿卡修斯是罗马的英雄。
受难
是给盗贼用的。
第814章
基督徒。
-这太常见了。
-他是个叛徒。他必须死。
我同意。
第817章
让大神们来决定吧
他在斗兽场的命运。
就让大神们来决定吧。
你知道吗，昨晚我醒来，
梦见一条黑暗的河流。
这次，
首次，
第821章
我正在穿越它。
第822章
嗯。
第823章
嗯，你知道，
我来自哪里，
第824章
过河，
它代表着宽恕。
第825章
代表……救赎。
第826章
我来自哪里，
这意味着你已经死了。
第827章
但正如我所看到的，
我并不害怕。
为了...
因为有人在等待
对于另一边的我来说。
第830章
那里。
第831章
这个人是谁？
第832章
被刮掉了？
第833章
马克西姆斯.
第834章
我见过他打架一次。
第835章
-他很伟大。
-毫米。
第836章
是的。我在赛场上的时光，
it was after his,
but many still talked of him
in whispers, you know?
Spoke of him.
What he did.
I met him once.
He was kind.
He bowed to no one.
Come with me.
-Hmm?
-Come. With me.
When a rebel gladiator dies,
we bury them here.
"What we do in life
echoes in eternity."
This is Argento.
This is Scatto.
Cheers.
And stop.
为了他的叛国罪
反对生命
第852章
皇帝的
和罗马国家，
第853章
贾斯图斯·阿卡修斯将军，
第854章
人民的敌人！
第855章
金合欢！金合欢！金合欢！
第856章
-我们爱你，阿卡修斯！
-你是英雄！
第857章
金合欢！金合欢！金合欢！
第858章
-Vae victis。
-一般的。
第859章
金合欢！
金合欢！金合欢！金合欢！
第861章
从
被征服的努米底亚城，
第862章
两次征服的胜利者
在斗兽场...
第863章
现在就去吧。 Vae 受害者。
第864章
汉诺！汉诺！汉诺！
Hanno!
Oh, Lord, any honor I have,
-I will give it to you!
-It's too late.
The Roman traitor or
the barbarian hero.
Let the gods decide.
Lucius... wait.
Wait! Wait!
I am a vessel.
Fill me with vengeance
and vanquish the betrayer.
-We love you, Acacius!
-Move it!
Pick it up!
Bravo, Hanno!
我们爱你，阿卡修斯！
你还在等什么？
第881章
你会死的！
第882章
我知道你是谁。
第883章
卢修斯·维鲁斯·奥勒留。
第884章
金合欢属
已经举手了！
第885章
他已经投降了。
第886章
就让大神们来决定吧。
第887章
诸神已经渲染了
他们的判断。
第888章
做你必须做的事。
第889章
但在我死后，
你必须知道...
我爱你的妈妈，
露西拉.
第891章
还有你的父亲...
第892章
马克西姆斯.
第893章
我会死的
为了他。
第894章
杀了他！
让他活下去吧！
请！
居住！居住！居住！居住！
第897章
杀了他！
弓箭手！
-不！
-杀了他！
金合欢！金合欢！
杀了他！
杀了他！杀了他！
金合欢！
不！
该死的你！
死亡将是
对你太好了！
罗马就是这样吗
对待英雄？
告诉我！
如果他的生命没有价值，
你的值多少钱？
大神们都发话了！
汉诺！汉诺！汉诺！汉诺！
为了我们自己的安全，
我们该回王宫了。
汉诺！汉诺！汉诺！
退后！退后！
阿利沙特！
我们讨价还价。
我把他给了你。
你让他活着。
你得到了
你想要什么。
我总能得到我想要的。
你为什么让他活着？
你买了一个角斗士，
不是奴隶。
我的意志是我自己的。
啊...
你的血有多蓝？
也许是罗马人的心
在那胸膛里跳动。
最伟大的寺庙
罗马曾经建成。
罗马斗兽场。
第932章
因为这是
他们相信什么。
第933章
力量。
第934章
他们聚集在这里观看
强者击倒弱者。
-一定还有别的东西。
-没有别的事了。
第936章
-必须有另一个罗马。
-没有第二个罗马。
第937章
-“梦想”？
-毫米。
罗马的梦想？
这是一个老人的幻想。
你是谁？
第941章
在你之前你叫什么名字
把它换成罗马的？
第942章
你永远不会知道。
第943章
我有一个命运。
第944章
众神把你交给了我。
第945章
你将成为我的乐器。
第946章
我永远不会成为你的工具
今生或来世。
第947章
那不会是我的命运。
But I will see your end.
What else could I do?
He and his bitch
were plotting to kill us.
Don't you hear them?
They're calling for our heads!
The Praetorians
will put down this crowd.
-Like they have every other.
-You brought this on us.
Filthy ape!
Perhaps you should, uh,
take Dondus elsewhere
to comfort him?
Forgive
my brother's outburst.
The disease
that infects his loins
has spread to his brain.
-Every day he gets worse.
-I will reason with him.
I see you.
Caracalla, Caracalla!
Come on, stand up.
Get up, get up.
Not you.
All right,
there you go.
Now, listen to me.
What's the matter?
Nothing's ever mine.
Everything is ours,
always.
Even in the womb...
he tried...
to cut my umbilicus
so that I couldn't have
any more air.
-You remember that, do you?
-Certainly.
-Come, sit.
-One cannot forget.
My conscience compels me.
What?
Sit.
Your brother
means to blame you
in front of
the entire Senate...
But I did not do it!
...for what's happening
in the streets.
-The chaos!
-He's lying!
No testimony
can be more damning
than one brother
against another.
That's a lie!
He always lies!
He can be very persuasive.
So?
What will they do to me?
Oh, I don't dare imagine.
But imagine this:
What will they do to Dondus?
What will they do
to Dondus?
It's your decision.
Brother.
Put down the blade.
You lie.
-Give it to me.
-You always lie!
Give it--
Look at me.
Look at me. Look at me.
-Lie!
-Listen to me. Break the spell.
-说谎！
-打破咒语！
我一直都在保护你。
因为我爱你。
回来。帮我。
卢修斯。
从来没有想象过
命运会把我们带到这里。
但我们现在就在这里。
一切都有
让我们回到了原点。
你送我走
然而命运
带我回到
他死的地方。
这枚戒指...
属于我父亲。
他把它给了你
父亲马克西姆斯，
作为信任的象征。
我把它给了阿卡修斯
为了他的英勇。
这枚戒指是我妻子的。
我会把它穿在你的旁边。
我真的为阿卡修斯感到抱歉。
我看不到那个人。
他是罗马的一名士兵。
有一个计划。
他正在准备军队
在奥斯蒂亚
指挥下
大流士塞克斯图斯。
他所率领的部队
反对皇帝。
金合欢属。马克西姆斯.
马库斯·奥勒留。
They lived and died
for Rome.
We all do.
Is it true
they intend to kill you?
One man or another has had
a sword against my neck
since the day
my father died.
But now
that I've found you,
it doesn't matter.
I am not afraid.
I've become well versed in
losing the things that I love.
But now that I've found you,
I have no desire
to lose you again.
-You stand like him.
-Mm.
Alert.
自豪的。
我没有他的实力。
我希望这是真的。
我希望我能告诉你
逃离这个地方。
现在就去吧。
实力与荣誉。
作为皇帝，
我已召集
参议院任命
我的第一任领事
并赋予他权力
管理军队
和公民职能
帝国的。
我命名...
公民唐杜斯！
唐杜斯万岁！
- 唐杜斯万岁。
- 唐达斯万岁！
唐杜斯万岁！
作为第二领事...
我命名...
公民...
马克里努斯！
马克里努斯万岁！
将会有一场胜利
游行庆祝。
会有游戏
和大规模处决。
帝国万岁！
坐下。
我碰巧有...
有好运
而且还没有一点技巧...
剩下的皇帝的耳朵。
我可以用逻辑来解释它...
并驯服疯狂
在街上。但...
恢复秩序...
我必须有权力...
和命令
凌驾于禁卫军之上。
选票...
或手？
-是啊！
鄙人。
Put your hands down.
You can sit down.
Rome must fall.
I need only
give it a push.
And after Rome falls...
...what then?
You are
your father's child.
His dream of Rome
was never a dream.
It was a fiction.
"The best revenge is
to become unlike the one
who did the injury."
I have made myself
unlike your father.
He spoke of dreams,
我说的是实话。
以及唯一的真相
在我的罗马
是法律
最强的。
我被拥有
由一位皇帝。
现在我控制着一个帝国。
除了罗马之外还有什么地方
一个人能做到吗？
你认识吗
我身上有你父亲的印记吗？
如果有什么的话
你需要...
在这最后的几个小时里，
我们将提供。
你的死将为我扫清道路
登上王位。
明天
会有比赛。
而对他们...
我会获胜。
拉维！
你能给我留言吗
早上到奥斯蒂亚？
奥斯蒂亚有什么？
有一支军队。
我问你
冒着风险，我的朋友，
在服务中
更伟大的事物。
乘车前往奥斯蒂亚。
拿着这个戒指
达流斯·塞克斯图斯将军。
你在听吗？
大流士塞克斯图斯。
他会知道的
作为阿卡修斯的戒指。
And, uh,
who shall I say has
sent me with this ring?
I am Lucius Verus Aurelius.
The Prince of Rome.
Tell him
I am summoning the army
to the defense
of a new Republic.
-Should I trust you?
-Yes.
-Should I?
Ravi! I need your keys.
Thank you.
Stop! Come back!
Who gave you this?
Lucius Verus Aurelius.
罗马王子。
我们必须杀掉露西拉吗？
第1139章
直到她去世为止，
你永远不会知道和平。
曾经。
人们爱她。
她的死会煽动暴徒。
第1142章
如果她死了，街上
愤怒地起来，
我将交付他们
卡拉卡拉的头
和人民
会为我喝彩。
那，我的朋友，
是政治。
-我们可以？
-是的。
第1147章
今天将是
你的最后一场战斗，冠军。
还有我们的主人
已赐予你...
the wooden sword of freedom.
But you have to
earn it first.
Today, you're gonna
defend your mother.
Wood or steel,
a point is still a point!
Wait for me.
In honor
of the acclamation
of Emperor Caracalla,
First Consul Dondus
and Second Consul Macrinus,
and as punishment for her
conspiracy against the empire,
for her calumnies against
the emperor's imperial bloodline
and for fomenting
military mutiny
和她的丈夫一起，
女王将面临
神圣的正义
第1162章
在手上
禁卫军的成员。
我不是将军。
但我们都是军人。
并且到现在为止，
我们不再为之奋斗
比另一天的生存还要重要。
第1167章
你会怎样
我们有吗？
嗯，你可以回来
到你的细胞
如果你不希望
去打这场仗。
或者...
第1171章
你可以加入我。
第1172章
并为自由而战
远远超出这些墙。
第1173章
是啊！
第1174章
曾经有一段时间
荣誉在罗马具有某种意义。
第1175章
在这个罗马
第1176章
我不再相信
存在的。
第1177章
我们必须找到它！
并知道这一点：
第1179章
死亡在哪里，我们就不在哪里。
我们在哪里，
第1181章
死亡不是！
第1182章
借我剑。
第1183章
实力与荣誉。
实力与荣誉！
第1187章
Let it not be said
that the emperor
is not merciful.
The queen will be granted
a single gladiator
to defend her against
the Praetorian Guard.
The champion, Hanno!
Hanno! Hanno! Hanno!
Yes!
Summon the cavalry.
Put this down at once.
This is war! Real war!
The army of Acacius is advancing
just outside of Rome, sir.
We can still
outflank them.
They have only
5,000 troops, no more.
我们有多少人？
六千。
也许更多。
骑车到门口
并握住它们。
肮脏的人渣！
卢修斯！
把弓给我。
走吧，我的儿子。卢修斯——
嘘嘘嘘嘘……
马！
什么都不会
杀了这个野蛮人？
我的名字是
卢修斯·维鲁斯·奥勒留！
一个人不会成为
皇帝仅凭血统。
必须用武力夺取
并强行保存。
你是这样的人吗
像这样？
我不为权力而战。
我为解放罗马而战
来自像你这样的男人
并将其归还给他们。
众神本身
希望罗马重生。
他们送我...
来完成这项任务。
如果你的神呢
派我来杀你？
啊？
是时候结束这一切了，马克林努斯！
哈！
实力与荣誉，
我的儿子。
你看着我说话。
我不知道是什么
说除了
我们都知道
太多的死亡。
让鲜血不再流淌
以暴政的名义。
我的祖父，
马库斯·奥勒留，
谈到一个梦想
那就是罗马。
我父亲的一个梦想，
马克西姆斯·德西穆斯·梅里迪乌斯，
第1232章
为之而死。
一个理想。
一座适合多人的城市
为有需要的人提供庇护。
一个值得为之奋斗的家。
马克西姆斯的家
一生都在捍卫。
第1237章
那个梦想消失了。
但我们敢...
重建那个梦想
一起？
你说什么？
是啊！
是啊！是啊！是啊！是啊！
母亲。
跟我说话吧，神父。